Anytime. Anywhere. Anyone.
The Thing is a horror, mystery, science fiction film directed by John Carpenter.
A research team in Antarctica is hunted by a shape-shifting
alien that assumes the appearance of its victims.
MacReady, played by Kurt Russell.
Childs, played by Keith David.
Blair, played by Wilford Brimley.
Nauls, played by T.K. Carter.
Palmer, played by David Clennon.
Dr. Copper, played by Richard Dysart.
The Thing is a 1982 American science fiction horror film directed by
John Carpenter from a screenplay by Bill Lancaster.
Based on the 1938 John W.
Campbell Jr.
novella Who Goes There?, it tells the story of a group of American researchers in Antarctica who encounter the
eponymous "Thing", an extraterrestrial life-form that assimilates, then imitates, other organisms.
The group is overcome by paranoia and conflict as they learn that they can no
longer trust each other and that any of them could be the Thing.
The film stars Kurt Russell as the team's helicopter pilot R.
MacReady, with A.
Wilford Brimley, T.
Carter, David Clennon, Keith David, Richard Dysart, Charles Hallahan, Peter
Maloney, Richard Masur, Donald Moffat, Joel Polis, and Thomas G.
Waites in supporting roles.
Production began in the mid-1970s as a faithful adaptation of the
novella, following 1951's The Thing from Another World.
The Thing went through several directors and writers, each with
different ideas on how to approach the story.
Filming lasted roughly twelve weeks, beginning in August 1981 and took place on refrigerated
sets in Los Angeles as well as in Juneau, Alaska, and Stewart, British Columbia.
Of the film's $15 million budget, $1.5 million was spent on Rob Bottin's creature effects, a mixture of chemicals, food
products, rubber, and mechanical parts turned by his large team into an alien capable of taking on any form.
The Thing was released in 1982 to negative reviews.
Critics praised the special effects achievements but criticized their visual
repulsiveness, while others found the characters poorly realized.
The film grossed $19.6 million during its theatrical run.
Many reasons have been cited for its failure to impress
audiences: competition from films such as E.T.
the Extra-Terrestrial, which offered an optimistic view of alien visitation; a summer that had been filled with successful science fiction
and fantasy films and an audience living through a recession, diametrically opposed to The Thing's nihilistic and bleak tone.
However, the film found a cult following when it was released on home video and television and it has
since been reappraised as one of the best science fiction and horror films ever made.
Numerous film makers have noted its influence on their work, and it has been
referred to in other media such as television and video games.
The Thing has spawned merchandise – including a 1982 novelization, comic book sequels, haunted house attractions, and
board games – as well as a video game of the same title and a 2011 prequel film of the same title.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, helicopter, space
marine, based on novel or book, isolation.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and mind_bending.